Finding Aid for Ann Arbor Rotary Club records, 1931-2008
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ann Arbor Rotary Club records 1931-2008
Ann Arbor Rotary Club.
4 linear feet
852172 Bk 2
Ann Arbor chapter of national service organization; administrative files, topical files, and publications.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were donated by the Ann Arbor Rotary Club (donor no. 5407 in 2008.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Ann Arbor Rotary Club was founded in July of 1916. The mission of the organization was to encourage, foster, and implement the ideals of Rotary International in the local community and throughout the world in ways that enhance the quality of life and human dignity, create greater understanding among all people, and advance the search for peace. In all of their activities, they strive to abide by the highest ethical standards and always be guided by the Rotary principle of 'Service Above Self.' (from Rotary Club's website)
The collection consists of four series: Administration, Music, Projects, and Publications and documents the club's institutional and community activities.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Societies, etc.
- Administration
  The Administration series consists of policies, membership details, speakers, and other similar institutional records.
  - Strategic Plan, 1997-2002 (Box 1)
  - Constitution and By Laws, 1973, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Board Policies and Procedures, 1968, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1998-2007 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, 1949-2004, 3 folders and 4 expandable folders (Box 1)
  - Finances, 1934-1945, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Membership
    - Lists
      - 1948 (Box 2)
      - 1992-1994 (Box 2)
    - Directories, 1971-1972 and 1997-2008, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Anniversaries (50th, 75th), 1966, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Award Certificates, 1996-2008 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1931-1934 and 1936-1937, 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Plans of Committees, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Speakers, 1965-1972 (Box 2)
  - Report to the District Governor of Club Committees, 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - Rotary Foundation Scholars Report, 1980, 1988 (Box 2)
  - University of Michigan Rotaract Club miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous
    - 1932-1934 (Box 2)
    - 1967-1983 (Box 2)
- Music
  The Music series contains the songs written for and by the rotary club.
  - Radio Broadcast, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Rotary Song Books, 1976 (Box 2)
- Projects
  The Projects series document the club's two international service endeavors in Peru and Sierra Leone.
  - Peru, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
  - Sierra Leone, 1993 (Box 2)
- Publications
  The majority of the Publications series contains a run of Harpoon, the club's newsletter. A directory for high school students and a history of the club are also included.
  - Harpoon (newsletter)
    - 1920-1922, 1 bound volume (Box 2)
    - 1921-1948, 28 folders (Box 3)
    - 1949-1982, 34 folders (Box 4)
    - 2000-2002 (Box 4)
    - 2004-2007, 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Undated (Box 4)
  - Directory of Occupational and Career Information, 1981 (Box 4)
  - A History of the Ann Arbor Rotary, 1916-1947 (Calvin O. Davis) (Box 4)
  - History, 1964-1970 and 1970-1980, 2 items in 1 folder (Box 4)